



As a strategist, my analytical and scientific background has enabled me to approach client challenges at the midpoint of art and science, I began my career in the music industry at the dawn of social media; an exciting time which provided a solid foundation stone for the fundamental principles of turning audiences into advocates.

I'm most passionate about leading clients towards a more sustainably-focused and purpose- driven future while still achieving growth and driving innovation, and I've worked with a wide mix of UK and global brands to help them achieve this.

Experience

Consultant Strategy Director

Redwood BDDO (July 2021 - present) freelance

- Strategy lead across Google, focused on developing a strategic roadmap and comms approach for Google's sustainability offering in the UK and globally.
- Lead content strategist across Google initiatives including Google Marketing Live and YouTube programmes.

Senior Strategist - Blue State (Mar 2018 - July 2021)

In my role at Blue State, I led strategic consultancy for government, third sector and brand clients including Lloyds Banking Group, Google, UNICEF, UNHCR, Tesco and UK Government.

Key achievements:

- Won and led content and creative strategy for Tesco, with revenue of £1m. I led the development of their CSR and social content approach, which included launching an audience and customer insight programme, including first party customer surveys and social listening.
- programme, including first party customer surveys and social listening.

 I developed Tesco's digital CSR and Purpose comms strategy and led a team of 3 creating CSR content for social and web.
- I led and implemented a 2-year innovation testing programme for Lloyds Banking Group. This included the development of Al-driven synthetic customer personas to act as proxies for the 'voice of the customer'.

Consultant Strategy Director (Sept 2016-Feb 2018)

Highlights included:

Golin (Dec 2017 - Feb 2018) freelance

Key achievements:

- Led audience insight and developed UK web/social content strategy for Danone brands and Magnum (Unilever).

VML (Oct - Dec 2017) freelance

Key achievements:

I led the content acquisition and retention strategy for The Olympic Channel and NBA clients.

Digitas LBi (Feb 2017 - Oct 2017) freelance

Key achievements:

- I developed the social content and campaign strategy for a number of key Kellogg's brands within an integrated agency team.
- This included development of a content and campaign strategy around Kellogg's CSR comms, aligned with supply chain and responsible sourcing as well as sugar reduction initiatives.
- I led research and insight development, briefing and developing creative ideas and ensured that ATL comms was data-led and on-strategy.

Southpaw (Sept 2016 - January 2017) freelance

Key achievements:

Brand strategy lead across multiple Diageo brands, leading strategic output across a number of winning pitches.

I led audience insight and development and led the content, campaign and channel strategy across several Diageo brands.

Content Director - OMD, International (Jan 2016 - August 2016)

Led a team of 3 Content Managers to develop innovative content and platform propositions across the OMD client portfolio, including work for Disney, Boots Laboratories, Estee Lauder and Intel.

Key achievements:

- Led the brand strategy development for the relaunch of Boots Laboratories range across 5 EMEA markets, managing a team of 3.
 Rolled out the global digital launch strategy for DKNY Fragrances / Estee Lauder across 12 markets.

Client Solutions Manager, Percolate (Sept 2015 - Jan 2016)

Made redundant due to global business restructure

Worked with senior Percolate clients to ensure business success and client retention by gaining an in-depth understanding of client's global marketing priorities.

Developed and implemented strategic approach for Huawei's global content workflows and successfully rolled out the Percolate platform to 7 of their brand and agency reams worldwide.

Head of Digital Strategy, August Media (September 2014 - Sept 2015)

Tasked with building a new department & growing the agency's digital offering, complementing their strong heritage in customer communications. Clients included IKEA, Gap, and Renault Sport.

Key achievements:

Established and grew the digital strategy team at August, managing a team of 4.

- Grew IKEA Family's digital offering from a UK-only content hub to a content network distributed across 20+ markets, driving content and platform innovation.
- Led the strategy for redeveloping the Renault Sport brand in digital.

Content and Community Director, 360i (Jan 2014 - September 2014)

Led in-house creative and strategy teams to develop and execute innovative social and web content. Clients included Enterprise Rent-a-Car, LV Insurance and TUI Travel (First Choice, Thomson)

Key achievements:

- Developed EMEA digital strategy for Enterprise Rent-a-Car and helped to develop their online content hub. Exceeded site KPI targets for acquisition and retention.
- Managed internal team of 7 and external contributors to deliver monthly content, developed editorial concepts and organized shoots.

Strategist, We Are Social (November 2011 - Jan 2014)

Digital brand strategy, planning and implementation for integrated campaigns (UK, EMEA and global) for FMCG / Travel clients including Expedia, Red Bull, Jaguar and Heineken.

Key achievements:

- Took Bulmers from a challenger brand in cider category to #1 cider brand in social media (2012, 2013)
- Developed global content production process for Jaguar in 10 markets

Marketing Manager, Holler (February 2009 - November 2011)

Managed content-led digital marketing and social media campaigns for clients including Red Bull, Unilever and Channel 4.

Previous Career: Music Industry (1999 - 2008)

• Events, digital marketing and PR for record labels, entertainment brands and artists

Qualifications

BSc hons, Pharmacology

2:2